# **Prem Sager**

<u>027-511-3822</u>

premsag@zoho.com

(Software Developer)

https://www.premsager.com/cv

https://www.linkedin.com/in/prem-sager-verma

## **Career Objective**

A highly focused and passionate software developer with around 3 years of experience in a variety of development positions and projects. My primary goal is to apply my technical expertise all throughout the full software life cycle to ensure the production and delivery of products and services that meet the client's specifications.

## **Key Skills:**

Frontend Skills	Backend Skills	Other Tools
HTML5	C#	Version Control:
CSS3	ASP.NET Core	GIT
0000	Restful WEB API	Azure DevOps Server
CSS Frameworks:	ORM:	Documentation Tools:
Bootstrap	EF Core	GitHub
Material UI	Dapper	Confluence
Semantic UI	ADO .NET	
Prototyping Tools:	Database:	Project Management:
Sketch	SQL Server	Scrum
Figma	SQLite	Trello
		Microsoft Planner
Modern JavaScript	API Tools:	
React	Postman	
React Hooks	Fiddler	
MobX		
Xdoivi		

#### Portfolio:

Please visit the following link for the portfolio.

#### **Work Experience:**

## Full Stack Developer @Freelancer

Feb 2020 - Present

Working on personal projects to put the most out of my learnings and some clients based in New Zealand.

Currently working with latest technologies like:

- 1. Implemented Onion Architecture (Clean Architecture).
- Mediator with CQRS pattern.
- 3. React Hooks and Context API.
- 4. Dapper and EF Core for Persistence.

## Junior Developer @IF Else Cloud Ltd. Dec 2018 - Jan 2020

KYPECO, Cloud base SAAS application which helps manufacturing plants to calculate there OEE and generate several real-time reports.

I was primarily working with the Web Development team with the following responsibilities:

- 1. Create Web APIs using EFCore Code first approach.
- 2. Consume API's in React application using React Hooks.
- 3. Building reusable react components.
- 4. Documentation using Confluence and GitHub.
- 5. Working with Postman and Fiddler to create Mock API's and validate the response.

# Junior Developer @Firstec Ltd.

Mar 2017 - Feb 2018

KMS, Kura Management System's main idea was to make customized learning plans for individual students. Along with various reporting patterns, which then helps to track their performances.

My main role in the development team was:

- 1. Working with Material UI, AngularJs (1.5x) and pure CSS.
- 2. Creating UI components from wireframes (I am familiar with Sketch and Adobe XD).
- 3. Writing Store procedures and SQL queries using Repository pattern.
- 4. EF Database first approach to create Restful API's.
- 5. Documentation, both technical and end-user manual using GitHub.

#### **Education:**

### **Specialization in Software Development**

Aspire2 International

Dec 2015- Mar 2017

Auckland, NZ

Successfully completed my Level 7 from Aspire2 International with 2 Minor projects and 1 Major with Auckland based client.

Main Subjects covered in depth during my studies:

- Strategic implementation of Information Systems
- IT Project Management
- Programming in C#

However, during my Internship, I Worked with AGILE methodology, creating web services using AZURE portal, familiarity with Azure Components- Application Insights, creating project charter and Giant charts. Also tested a number of projects as assignments in Selenium tool. The focus of my course surrounds around JavaScript frameworks especially AngularJS and its integration.

#### **Master of Computer Applications**

**GJ** University

Jun 2014- Nov 2015

Hissar, India

My study cum work experience during my earlier studies, polish my skills in C# .NET and ASP .NET along with different Data Servers like MS SQL Server, MS Access etc.

#### **Bachelor of Computer Applications**

Kurukshetra University

Jun 2010- Dec 2013

Kurukshetra India

- Certificate of 6 months Industrial Training from Technaitra Solutions.
- Certificate of 2nd Position at Robo-Tryst organized by IIT Delhi.

Reference: Available on request.